ILGWU. Charles Zimmerman Collection of Radical Pamphlets 5780/178
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
ILGWU. Charles Zimmerman Collection of Radical Pamphlets
1914-1958.
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Charles S. Zimmerman, 1896-1983
5780/178
11 cubic feet
6 linear feet
Pamphlets
This collection contains pamphlets collected by Charles Zimmerman of the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union.
7461936
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff
Date completed:
2003
EAD encoding:
Casey Westerman, 2003Cheryl Beredo, August 2011
Biographical / Historical
The International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union was founded in New York City in 1900 by mostly Socialist immigrant workers who sought to unite the various crafts in the growing women's garment industry. The union soon reflected changes in the sector and rapidly organized thousands of unskilled and semi-skilled women, mostly Jewish and Italian young immigrants. Exemplifying the "new unionism," the ILGWU led two of the most widespread and best-known industrial strikes of the early Twentieth Century: the shirtwaist makers' strike of 1909 in New York City and the cloak makers' strike of 1910 in Chicago. The union also tried to adapt to the fragmented and unstable nature of the industry. It adopted the "protocol of peace," a system of industrial relations that attempted to ensure stability and limit strikes and production disruption by providing for an arbitration system to resolve disputes.
The ILGWU exemplified the European-style social unionism of its founding members. They pursued bread and butter issues but provided educational opportunities, benefits, and social programs to union members as well. In 1919, the ILGWU became the first American union to negotiate an unemployment compensation fund that was contributed to by its employers. The ILGWU also pioneered in the establishment of an extremely progressive health care program for its members which included not only regional Union Health Centers but also a resort for union workers, known as Unity House. The Union also had an imaginative and pioneering Education Department which not only trained workers in traditional union techniques, but provided courses in citizenship and the English language.
David Dubinsky, an immigrant from Belarus who came to the US in 1911, provided strong leadership that led to unprecedented growth in the union during his presidency from 1932 to 1966. He led the union through successful internal anti-communist struggles, built on the ascendancy of industrial unionism by encouraging the formation of the Committee for Industrial Organization, and helped the union become an important political force in New York City and state politics, and in the national Democratic Party and Liberal Party as well.
In the period following the Second World War, the union suffered a decline in membership as manufacturers avoided unionization and took advantage of less expensive labor by moving shops from the urban centers in the northeast to the south, and later abroad. The ethnic and racial character of the ILGWU also changed as European immigrants were supplanted by Asians, Latin Americans, African- Americans, and immigrants from the Caribbean.
In July 1995 the ILGWU merged with the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union (ACTWU) at a joint convention, forming UNITE (Union of Needletrades, Industrial and Textile Employees). At the time the new union had a membership of about 250,000 in the United States, Canada, and Puerto Rico.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains pamphlets collected by Charles Zimmerman of the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials. This collection must be used in keeping with the Kheel Center Information Sheet and Procedures for Document Use.
Related Materials
5780. ILGWU records
5780/014. ILGWU. Local 22. Charles S. Zimmerman papers
5780/014 P. ILGWU. Local 22. Charles S. Zimmerman photographs
Arrangement
b Pamphlets are arranged alphabetically by author's name or title.
Women's clothing industry -- United States; Clothing workers -- Labor unions -- United States; Clothing workers -- United States; Industrial relations -- United States; Zimmerman, Charles S.,1896-1983; Zimmerman, Charles S., 1896-1983; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union
7461936
- Negro Labor Committee. First anniversary, the Negro Labor Committee, a year of the most constructive work among negroes since emancipation, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Communist International. Executive Committee. XIth plenum of the Executive Committee of the Communist International theses, resolutions and decisions., 1931 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Communist International. Executive Committee. 15 years of the Communist International., 1934 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- 30 caricatures de la Guerra, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Scope and Contents
  Spanish
- American Federation of Labor (AFL). Welcome officers, delegates and visitors to the 69th Convention of the American Federation of Labor: Program., 1950 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- United States. Congress. House. Committee on Un-American Activities. 100 things you should know about communism in the U.S.A., 1948 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Earl Browder. Di Yunyons, der Fareynikter Front, di Leybor Partey, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Yiddish
- Friedrich Engels. Der Visenshaftlikher Sotsyalizm, 1907 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  Yiddish, some text on the cover uses the Ukrainian or Rusyn alphabet
- N. Chanin. Lektsyes farn yor 1936-1937 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- N. Chanin. Lektsyes farn yor 1938-1939 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- S. Rotman. Treyd Yunyonizm un Zayne Itstige Metoden, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- R. Zaltsman. A Groyser Farbrekhn: vi Azoi di Firer dem Idishn Arbeter-Komitet Fartakhleven Relif-Gelter, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Ven Hoben di Komunisten emes Gezogt, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Leopold Cohn. Gloyben Kristen in 3 Geter (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Yiddish. Do Christians Worship Three Gods
- P. Kurinsky. Kapitalistishe un Sotsyalistishe Moral un de "False Pasportnikes" (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Der Krizis un di Nodl-Fakhn, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Bundishe Pretenzies un di Virklekhkayt, 1944-1946 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  Yiddish. Fiction and Truth: A Reply to the Attacks of the Jewish Bundists on the Jewish Conference and Zionism
- Resolutsii VIII S'Ezda, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  Russian
- I. Hart. Henryk Erlich un Viktor Alter, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Unzere Itstige Oyfgabn, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- E. Mus. Sovyet-Rusland: Unzer Tragedye, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Idishe Arbeter oyf der Hoykh fun Zeyer Oyfgabe, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- B. Hoffman. Komunisten vos Hoben Oyfgegesen der Komunizm, 1923 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Barikht fun Hyu Yorker Arbeter ring Divisie farn Gemaynshaftlekh Kampeyn fu Idishn Arbeter Komitet un "Ort", 1942 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  Yiddish. Der Kamf Geyt On. Report of the New York Workmen's Circle Division, Jewish Labor Committee and "ORT"
- F. Gelibter. Lektsyes, 1935-1936 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Rekht Far Idn in Nayem Poyln, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- F. Shrager. Eydn in Frankraykh, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Di Platforme fun Klasnkamf, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Yiddish title not translated, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  Yiddish. No cover or title page
- Professionalnoe Dvizhenie Robochik Shveinoi Promishlennocti, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Der Kamf far di Rentn fun di Arbeter, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Petr Kropotkin. Gosudarstvo, ego rol v istorii, 1904 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  Rusyn [Russian]
- N. Bukharin. Proletarisher Alef-Beys, 1922 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Karl Marx; Friedrich Engels. Der Komunistisher Manifest, 1919 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Nathaniel Buchwald. Alts: far Unzer Land Amerike, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Darf Amerike Arayn in der Milhome?, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Moshe Erem. Idishe un Arabishe Arbet in Erets-Yisroel, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Alexander Bittelman. Vos Arbeter-Aynigkayt kon Oyfton tsu Farvirklekhn di Bashlusn fun der Rozvelt-Stalin-Txhzirtshil Fonferents, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 38)
- Shloyme Mendelson. Der Vidershtand in Varshever Geto, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 39)
- F. Lassal. Di Arbeyter un di Gezelshaftlikhe Klasen: Iberzetst fun Daytsh, 1906 (Box 1, Folder 40)
- Communist International. Rezolutsyes fun 5tn Kongres un Konstitutsye fun Komunistishn Internatsyonal, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  Yiddish. Vos hot oyfgeton der 5-ter Kongres fun Komunistishn Internatsyonal
- Mosheh Kats. Der 1ter May 1937: Mit vos Mir Kumen tsu im un vos Fodern (Box 1, Folder 42)
- Morris Hillquit; Hannah Goldstein Salutsky. Der Sotsyalizm: Zayne Urzakhen, Tsielen un Vegen, 1915 (Box 1, Folder 43)
- National Urban League. ABC of labor problems, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 44)
- League of Women Voters. The ABC of the USA, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 45)
- Charles Abrams. A housing program for America, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 46)
- Communist Party of the United States. Convention.. Acceptance speeches: Communist candidates in the presidential elections, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 47)
- Sozialdemokratische Partei Deutschlands. Action program of the Social Democratic Party of Germany, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  Adopted by the party conference at Dortmund, September 28, 1952.
- Mildred Adams; William W. Wade. Britain's road to recovery; Socialism and the King's English, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 49)
- Friedrich Adler. Democracy and revolution, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  by Friedrich Adler, secretary of the Labor and socialist international.
- Alex Bittelman. The Advance of the United Front, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 51)
- AFL-CIO. AFL-CIO no-raiding agreement, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 52)
- AFL. A. F. of L. vs. C. I. O.: the record, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 53)
- AFL-CIO. AFL-CIO song book, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 54)
- Jewish Labor Committee. A.F. of L. fights bigotry! (Box 1, Folder 55)
- AFL. A.F.L. wants F.E.P.C. (Box 1, Folder 56)
- Aid for the unemployed: and how to get it. (Box 1, Folder 57)
- James S. Allen. Negro liberation, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 58)
- Gordon W. Allport. The bigot in our midst: an analysis of his psychology (Box 1, Folder 60)
- Ethel Josephine Alpenfels; Louise E. Jefferson. Sense and nonsense about race, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  Drawings by Louise E. Jefferson
- A. Aluf. The development of socialist methods and forms of labour, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  From the first Subbotnik to the present vast scope of socialist competition
- National Planning Association. America's new opportunities in world trade, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 63)
- American committee for non-participation in Japanese aggression. America's share in Japan's war guilt, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 64)
- America and the winning of the peace, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 65)
- American Committee for Cultural Freedom. American Committee for Cultural Freedom, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 66)
- American CP writes its own epitaph: Earl Browder's New Constitution, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 67)
- American Federation of Labor. American Federation of Labor, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 68)
- American Federation of Labor. Answers to your questions about unions (Box 1, Folder 69)
- American Federation of Labor. Free Trade Union Committee. American labor looks at the world, 1948-1951 (Box 1, Folder 70)
  no.2-3 (1948-1949), no.5 (1951)
- American labor monthly, 1923 (Box 1, Folder 71)
  1923 (May, July, October)
- American labor monthly, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 72)
  1924 (February, July, August)
- Spencer Miller. American labor and the nation, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 73)
- American Labor Party. American Labor Party; Handbook, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 74)
- American labor to the rescue, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 75)
  Addresses delivered by prominent American and European leaders of labor at the opening session of the National Conference of the Jewish Labor Committee held at Carnegie Hall, New York City on January 17th, 1941.
- American Legion and the communists discuss democracy, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 76)
- Beulah Amidon Ratliff. Jobs after forty, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 77)
- Israel Amter. Industrial slavery Roosevelt's "New Deal", 1933 (Box 1, Folder 78)
- Israel Amter. The truth about the Communists (Box 1, Folder 79)
- Israel Amter. Why the workers' unemployment insurance bill?, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 80)
- Israel Amter. Working class unity or fascism?, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 81)
- Alexander Berkman; Emma Goldman. Anarchism on trial, 1917 (Box 1, Folder 82)
  Speeches of Alexander Berkman and Emma Goldman before the United States District Court in the city of New York, July, 1917.
- Benjamin M. Anderson. Types of social radicalism, 1927 (Box 1, Folder 83)
- Frank Anderson; David J. Saposs. A reading list of the American Federation of Labor, 1923 (Box 1, Folder 84)
- Annual daybreak dance of the modern school of Stelton, N.J., 1949 (Box 1, Folder 85)
  Friday, December 9, 1949
- Program and aims of ANTIFA (Box 1, Folder 86)
  Palestinian League Against War and Fascism and for Jewish-Arab Solidarity
- Anti-imperialist review, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 87)
  v.1:no.6 (1932:July-August)
- Revolutionary Policy Committee. An appeal to the membership of the Socialist Party, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 88)
- Clare Booth Luce; William Henry Chamberlin; William Z. Foster; Harry F. Ward. Are communism and democracy mutually antagonistic?, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 89)
- Are they fooling you?, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 90)
- Are you getting good neighbors? (Box 1, Folder 91)
- Gregor Aronson; Benjamin Schultz. Soviet Russia and the Jews, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 92)
  Translated by Benjamin Schultz from the original Yiddish
- Attention Mr. Dies!: what prominent Americans say about the Un-American Dies Committee. (Box 1, Folder 93)
- The axis in defeat. A collection of documents on American policy toward Germany and Japan., 1945 (Box 1, Folder 94)
- Manuel Azana. Speech delivered by don Manuel Azana, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 95)
  President of the Spanish Republic: in Barcelona City Hall on July 18, 1938.
- John Stothoff Badeau. East and west of Suez; the story of the modern Near East, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  Illustrated by Graphic Associates
- H. Sabin Bagger. See here, private enterprise! A birdseye book clarifying current controversies, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Thomas Andrew Bailey. America's foreign policies: past and present, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Helen Baker. A trade union library, 1935 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Angelica Balabanoff. Traitor: Benito Mussolini and his "Conquest" of power, 1942-1943 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Joseph Hurst Ball. Collective security: the why and how, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Gustav Bang; Arnold Petersen. Crises in European history, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  Translated from the Danish by Arnold Petersen.
- Jack Barbash. The labor movement in the United States, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Noah Barou. Recent trends in British trade unions, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  British trade union congress' Interim report on postwar reconstruction, a summary
- Be Wise Organize (Box 2, Folder 10)
  No title page
- Fred Erwin Beal; Ferdinand Lundberg; James T. Farrell. The red fraud: an expose of Stalinism, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  introduction by Ferdinand Lundberg; preface by James T. Farrell. 3 copies
- Charles Austin Beard. Jefferson, corporations and the Constitution, 1936 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Thomas Bell. The movement for world trade union unity, 1925 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Herbert Benjamin. A handbook for project workers, 1936 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Benjamin Franklin vindicated: an exposure of the Franklin "prophecy", 1939 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Mrs. Victor Berger. I saw Russia: socialism in the making, 1935 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Edward L. Bernays. Human relations: the way to labor-management adjustments, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Beware the Sixth Column (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Alex Bittelman. From left-socialism to communism, 1933 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Alex Bittelman. Going left; the Left Wing formulates a "Draft for a program for the Socialist Party of the United States", 1936 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Alex Bittelman. The Jewish people will live on!, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Alex Bittelman. Problems of party building, 1937 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Van A. Bittner. Labor and Religion (Box 2, Folder 23)
  Address by Van A. Bittner delivered at The Cathedral Church of St. Paul in Boston, Massachusetts
- Frank B. Blumenfield. A blueprint for fascism: what the industrial mobilization plan holds for America, 1937 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Blair Bolles. Who makes our foreign policy?, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Claude Gernade Bowers; Earl Browder; Francis Franklin; Alexander Trachtenberg. The heritage of Jefferson, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  Introduction by Alexander Trachtenberg
- Louis Dembitz Brandeis. A call to the educated Jew, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Mikhail Shipkov; Maynard Bertram Barnes. Breakdown: telling how the communist secret police are able to pry confessions of treason out of men and women who love their country, a story courageously laid bare for the first time in March 1950. (Box 2, Folder 28)
  With a profile by Maynard Bertram Barnes.
- Catherine Breshkovsky; George Kennan. A message to the American people (Box 2, Folder 29)
  Introduction by George Kennan
- Catherine Breshkovsky. Russia and the world; what is bolshevism? what we are fighting for Russia and the allies, Russia and the league of nations, Russia will emerge free, strong and united!, 1919 (Box 2, Folder 30)
- Harry Bridges Defense Committee. The Bridges showdown, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 31)
- Oliver Brown, Mrs. Richard Lawton, Mrs. Sadie Emmanuel, et al. Appellants, vs. Board of Education of Topeka, Shawnee County, Kansas, et al.: Brief for the Congress of Industrial Organizations as Amicus Curiae, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  In the Supreme Court of the United States, October Term, 1952; No.8
- A brief history of the United Cement, Lime, and Gypsum Workers International Union (AFL-CIO,CLC)., 1978 (Box 2, Folder 33)
- A brief to the Premier of Ontario, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 34)
- Labour Party (Great Britain). Reconstruction in war and peace / The Old World and the New Society, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  Interim report of the National Executive Committee of the British Labor Party, approved by the party conference under the title "The old world and the new society.".
- British labor and Zionism; are these pledges and this record to be forgotten now?, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 36)
- Howell Hamilton Broach. Thurman Arnold's crusade; is it trust busting or union busting?, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 37)
- Earl Browder. America's decisive battle, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 38)
- Earl Browder. America and the second imperialist war, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 39)
- Earl Browder. Civil war in Nationalist China, 1927 (Box 2, Folder 40)
- Earl Browder. Class struggle vs. class collaboration: a study of labor banks, the B. & O. Plan, insurance schemes, and "workers' education", 1924 (Box 2, Folder 41)
- Earl Browder. Democracy or fascism, 1936 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  Report of the Central Committee to the ninth National Convention of the Communist Party of U.S.A., and speech in reply to discussion, delivered by Earl Browder, June 24, 1936.
- Earl Browder. The democratic front: for jobs, security, democracy and peace, 1938 (Box 2, Folder 43)
- Earl Browder. Economic problems of the war and peace, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 44)
- Earl Browder. Fighting for peace, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 45)
- Earl Browder; Jack Stachel. How do we raise the question of a labor party?, 1935 (Box 2, Folder 46)
- Earl Browder. Lenin and Spain, 1937 (Box 2, Folder 47)
- Earl Browder. Lincoln and the communists, 1936 (Box 2, Folder 48)
- Earl Browder. The meaning of the elections, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 49)
- Earl Browder. The meaning of social-fascism: its historical and theoretical background, 1933 (Box 2, Folder 50)
- Earl Browder. A Message to Catholics, 1938 (Box 2, Folder 51)
- Earl Browder. Next Steps to Win the War in Spain, 1938 (Box 2, Folder 52)
- Earl Browder. One year since Pearl Harbor, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 53)
- Earl Browder. The people's front in America, 1936 (Box 2, Folder 54)
- Earl Browder. Production for victory, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 55)
- Earl Browder. Religion and communism, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 56)
- Earl Browder. The road ahead to victory and lasting peace, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 57)
- Earl Browder. Social and national security, 1938 (Box 2, Folder 58)
- Earl Browder. Talks to America, 1937 (Box 2, Folder 59)
- Earl Browder. Trotskyism against world peace, 1937 (Box 2, Folder 60)
- Earl Browder. Victory -- and after, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 61)
- Earl Browder. War against workers' Russia!, 1931 (Box 2, Folder 62)
- Earl Browder. Whose war is it?, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 63)
- George Thomas Brown. Economic power in the United States, 1937 (Box 2, Folder 64)
- Irving Brown. Les Syndicates Americans et les Problems Internationaux (Box 2, Folder 65)
- William Montgomery Brown. Communism and Christianism, analyzed and contrasted from the Marxian and Darwinian points of view, 1922 (Box 2, Folder 66)
- William Montgomery Brown. The American race problem, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 67)
- William Montgomery Brown. The Pope's crusade against the Soviet Union, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 68)
- William Montgomery Brown. The godly bishops and the godless Bolsheviks, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 69)
- Martin Buber; Judah L. Magnes; Moses Smilansky. Palestine, a bi-national state, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 70)
- Nikolai Ivanovich Bukharin. Programme of the world revolution, 1920 (Box 2, Folder 71)
- Louis F. Budenz. May day 1937: what it means to you (Box 2, Folder 72)
- Louis F. Budenz; Earl Browder. Red baiting: enemy of labor, 1937 (Box 2, Folder 73)
  With a letter to Homer Martin by Earl Browder
- Louis F. Budenz. Save your union! the meaning of the 'anti-trust' persecution of labor, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 74)
- Bulgaria, a new Spain: the communist terror in Bulgaria, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 75)
  Published by Alexander Berkman Aid Fund in conjunction with the Committee for Aid to Bulgaria Anti-Fascists of Paris, France
- William C. Bullitt. The Bullitt mission to Russia, 1919 (Box 2, Folder 76)
  Testimony before the Committee on Foreign Relations, United States Senate, of William C. Bullitt.
- Grace M. Burnham. Work or wages, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 77)
- Alexander Calder; James L. Knipe. The guaranteed annual wage, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 78)
- Capitalist stabilization has ended; thesis and resolutions of the twelfth plenum of the Executive committee of the Communist International., 1932 (Box 2, Folder 79)
- B. Cantor. The end to wars (Box 2, Folder 80)
- Harry James Carman. An outline of the social and political history of the United States, a syllabus for study classes, 1927 (Box 2, Folder 81)
- William George Carr. Only by understanding, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 82)
- Mollie Ray Carroll. The American Federation of Labor: a discussion outline for trade union groups, 1935 (Box 2, Folder 83)
- Mollie Ray Carroll; Spencer Miller. American workers' education: its meaning, methods, and policies, 1936 (Box 2, Folder 84)
- Camille Huysmans. The case of Henryk Erlich and Victor Alter, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 85)
  Foreword by Camille Huysmans.
- The case for industrial organization., 1936 (Box 2, Folder 86)
- The case for the union shop., 1956 (Box 2, Folder 87)
- Catholic evidence on Spain: assembled from Catholic sources, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 88)
- Catholics and the civil war in Spain: a collection of statements by world-famous Catholic leaders on the events in Spain., 1936 (Box 2, Folder 89)
- Marine Workers and Boilermakers Industrial Union.. Centralized shipping bureau, 1934 (Box 2, Folder 90)
- Champlin's Developers (Box 2, Folder 91)
  not cataloged only a price list
- Abraham Chapman. Nazi penetration in America, 1939 (Box 2, Folder 92)